It's Sunday night. You just had a nice meal,
现在是星期天晚上 你刚享用了一顿美味的晚餐
maybe some dessert, and you're on the couch with
可能是一些甜点 你正躺在沙发里
some popcorn and you want to watch a movie.
手里拿着爆米花 你想看一部电影
How do you pick what to watch?
你如何挑选想看的电影呢？
Being a data driven person,
作为一个受数据驱动型的人
I love to check the ratings and reviews on Rotten Tomatoes,
我喜欢在烂番茄网站上查看影片的评分和影评
which is a popular movie rating website.
这是一个很受欢迎的电影评分网站
This list they have here is so useful.
它们在其中提供的清单很有用
The Rotten Tomatoes top 100 movies of all time list.
烂番茄史上排名前 100 位的电影清单
As written here, movies with 40 or more critic reviews are eligible for this list.
正如这里写到的 有 40 篇及以上的影评人影评的电影才有资格入选该名单
That's critic reviews, so ratings from
这就是影评人影评 所以 你我这样的普通电影观众的评分
regular movie watchers like you and me aren't included in these calculations.
是不包括在计算之列的
It's sorted by this adjusted score metric which combines
该名单是按照这个调整后分数指标排列的
the rating and number of critic reviews for each movie to create this adjusted score.
该指标结合了各部电影的影评人影评评分和数量
The idea being that movies with fewer critic ratings have
这样的话 影评人评分越少的电影
an easier path to getting that 100% score or close to it.
更容易得到 100% 或相近分数
Let's scroll a bit here.
我们稍稍滚动一下
Okay, so E.T., I've never actually seen
好吧 就《ET外星人》吧 尽管听说过很多关于它的消息
Steven Spielberg's 1982 masterpiece despite hearing lots about it.
实际上我从来没看过这部史蒂芬·斯皮尔伯格 1982 年的杰作
It's currently 11th on this list with a 98% rating and 114 critic reviews.
目前在名单上排名第 11 位 评分为 98% 有 114 篇影评人影评
Let's check it out. Okay, so there's that 98% rating.
我们来一探究竟吧 好吧 评分为 98%
This number is a bit deceiving though.
虽然 这个数字有点欺骗性
It's actually the Tomatometer score,
但它确实是烂番茄评分系统的评分
which is the percentage of
是给这部电影正面评论的
approved Tomatometer critics who have given the movie a positive review.
经核准烂番茄评分系统影评人所占的百分比
But okay, there's this audience score here, 72%.
不过 好吧 这里有观众评分 72%
That metric wasn't included in that top 100 list.
这个指标并未包括在前 100 名影片名单之中
That's a pretty massive gap.
这是一个相当大的差距
Maybe this movie isn't that amazing.
或许这部电影并没有那么优秀
Also, wouldn't it be cool to compare this critic's score and also the audience score
另外 将所有电影的影评人评分与观众评分进行比较
for all of these movies to see which movie really truly is the best?
看看哪部电影确实是最优秀的电影 不是很好吗
Also to find the worst best movie if you will.
另外 如果你愿意的话 还可以找出最糟糕的电影
I'm picturing a scatterplot with four quadrants,
我在绘制一幅有四个象限的散点图
like this one, but with different axis labels and values.
就像这幅图 但轴标签和值不同
We'd have audience score on the horizontal axis and critics score on the vertical one.
我们将观众评分作为横轴 影评人评分作为纵轴
That would put amazing movies with
这样 观众评分和影评人评分都高的神奇影片
high audience and critics scores in the top right quadrant
居于右上象限内
then critically underrated movies in the bottom
接着 影评人评分较低的影片居于右下象限内
right quadrant with high audience scores and low critics scores,
它们的观众评分高 但影评人评分低
and critically overrated movies in the top
影评人评分过高的影片处于左上象限
left with low audience scores and high critics scores.
它们的观众评分较低 但影评人评分较高
Also, I don't trust every single reviewer necessarily.
另外 我不一定相信每一个评论者
One person I do though,
但有一个人我相信
the late great Roger Ebert.
即刚刚去世的伟大的 Roger Ebert
For lots of people,
对许多人而言
Roger Ebert's was the only review they needed because he explained the movie in
Roger Ebert 的影评是他们需要的唯一影评 因为他解释电影的方式
such a way that they would know whether they would
使他们会知道他们
like it or not, his opinion notwithstanding.
是否喜欢这部电影 无论他本人是什么看法
Wouldn't it be neat if we had a word cloud for each of the movies in
如果我们有一个百佳电影名单中每部电影的 word cloud
that top 100 list with Roger Ebert's review text in that word cloud for each movie?
其中包括 Roger Ebert 的影评文本 难道不会非常清晰明白么？
This cool little word cloud generator in Python can help us out.
Python 中这个奇妙的 word cloud 生成器能够帮助我们
Having a word cloud for each movie would give us
为每部电影生成一个 word cloud 会让我们
a snapshot of what makes each movie great.
初步了解到电影怎样才会变得伟大
This word cloud library also has the ability to use stencils,
word cloud 库也具有使用模板的能力
so we could take the movie poster for each movie and surround it with
所以 我们可以使用每部电影的电影海报 用模板将其围绕起来
a stencil and then put the word cloud around the poster image.
然后将 word cloud 放在海报图像周围
That'd be really cool. So, to create both of these visualizations,
这样确实很酷 所以 为了创造出这两种可视化效果
the data is in a few different spots and
数据放在一些不同的位置
it will require some craftiness to gather it all,
它需要一些技巧才能全部收集齐
but you can definitely do it.
但你肯定能做到
This is actually going to be so awesome.
这肯定会很棒
I'm so excited for you to see the final products.
我很期待你们见到最终的产品